Chandler Hanson

Sammamish, WA 98074 | 425-786-8395 | chan.hanson5@gmail.com

Github: Chanson9892 | https://chandler-hanson.medium.com/ | www.linkedin.com/in/chandler-hanson | portfolio website: https://chanson9892.github.io/portfolio/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in physics and math. Focused on solving problems and finding solutions through code. I bring strong skills in collaboration and communication to translate customer needs into resolutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React.js, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Github, and Matlab.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Recipe Finder - Github Frontend Github Backend | Demo

Recipe Finder app, search for recipes and filter to include specific ingredients

- Created a single page application with a React frontend and a Rails backend.
- Connected with an external API to fetch and update information.
- Built search feature to grab specific recipes based on the user's search input.
- Applied JWT authorization (sign in) to have full access to the application.

Note Taker - Github | Demo

App for note taking, organizing, and task management

- Created a single page application with a React frontend that communicates with the Rails backend.
- Assembled full CRUD through fetch requests and setting state on React frontend.
- Built filter and sort features to reorganize notes.
- Transferred and update state throughout multiple components.

Breakout - Github Frontend Github Backend | Demo

Recreation of Atari's classic arcade game Breakout

- Built a single page application with a JavaScript frontend.
- Developed a Rails API backend that communicates with the JavaScript frontend.
- Utilized Canvas, getContext(), and setInterval() methods to express animations throughout the game.
- Designed event handlers to show proper gameplay mechanics.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Seattle, WA

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React.js programming to create full stack web applications.

08/2020 - 12/2020

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

Bachelors of Science (B.S.) in Earth and Space Science (Physics focus) and Physics Minor. Leadership position in my social club. Dean's list recipient 09/2016 - 06/2020

EXPERIENCE

Dick's Sporting Goods

Issaquah, WA

Cashier and Sales Member

06/2019 - 09/2019

- Collaborated with customers and coworkers to provide excellent customer service.
- Demonstrated strong product knowledge and understanding of target customers.

Big 5 Sporting Goods

Issaguah, WA

Cashier and Sales Member

06/2017 - 09/2017

- Promoted positive customer experiences and interactions in-person and on the phone.
- Registered customers for outdoor sporting licenses and educated them on restrictions.